We cannot keep on following the USA's war tank.
We have nothing to do within NATO.
We do not agree with the setting up of military bases in Poland, Lithuania,
or elsewhere to wage war on Russia.
France is not a "Western nation"
in the way that the USA defines "the West",
which includes some "Western countries" as unconvincing as Japan.
We are a universalist nation, present on all five continents.
Our largest border is the border with Brazil, not Germany.
Therefore, France should be the fulcrum of a new altermundialist world alliance,
with the aim of respecting the sovereignty of each people,
and applying the conventions and standards of the ILO and the UN.
They are the only references of international law preliminary to the use of force,
whereas today, force is being used before diplomacy.
We should stick to this political principle.
France can do it.
We are members of the Security Council and we are present on all five continents.
We have the capacity to do this.